Guide to the Swaziland Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Swaziland collection
1907-2002
MS 1544
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.27
(6 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to political and social conditions in Swaziland.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to political and social conditions in Swaziland.
Swaziland -- Politics and government; Swaziland -- Social conditions; Photographs -- Swaziland
- Inventory, 1907-1989
  - United Nations General Assembly: petition from S. J. Zwane, Chief External Representative, Ngwane National Liberatory Congress (NNLC), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Imbokodvo National Movement: news bulletin on United Nations Day, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Swaziland Government Information Services: news bulletins, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, popular, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dzadze: Swaziland's First Women's Magazine, 1987 Feb/March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - University of Swaziland: memorandum to all students in response to a student class boycott, 1989 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - King Mswati III: a 21st birthday souvenir booklet, 1989 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Caminho de Ferro de Swazilandia": photograph album, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Swaziland": exhibit photographs by Hew Dalrymple (includes brochures and listing), 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1969-1998; Accession 1997-M-174
  - Additional printed materials, 1969-1998, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1967-2002; Accession 2006-M-090
  - AIDS Supplement to The Nation, 2001 December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - MOAC Employees' Newsletter (Ministry of Agriculture and Cooperatives), 1996 Mar, June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Regional AIDS Training Network Newsletter, 2002 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Swaziland: The Current State of Play," Report No. 49, South African Institute of International Affairs, 1983 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Swaziland Student, Swaziland Students' Union, 1967 Jul/October-1968 Apr/June (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession 2010-M-116
  - Fabric: Bayethe Ngwenyama, King Mswati III, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1973-circa 2010; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1973-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, Circa 2010 (Folder 2)